we've been given an array
and a hash and we need to move the
information
from the array into the empty hash that
applies to each person
so we can look at our array on lines one
and two contact data
and see that this is a two-dimensional
array
we have two elements in the array and
each sub-array has
three elements which are strings and
they seem to reflect the
email address and phone number of two
people
joe and sally so now looking down on
line four
we have a hash contacts
and this hash has two key value pairs
the keys are strings with the names joe
and sally
and the values are empty hashes
so what we want to do here is to
populate the values of this contact's
hash
with the information about each
individual
let's see how we might access the
information about each individual that's
stored in the contact data array
so i'm going to use p to output this
and let's use array element reference
just to display the
subarray that contains the information
about joe
there's our subarray
and we were able to access that with the
index 0
since arrays have a 0 based index
now in order to access these elements
within the subarray
these strings we can chain another
element reference on here
so our first element reference returns
the subarray
and let's say we want to retrieve the
email
we'll chain another element reference
here to return the element at index 0 of
our subarray
running our code again there we see the
email
so now that we know how we're going to
access the information
about these individuals from the contact
data array
we need to think about how we're going
to populate the hash
associated with each key in our contacts
hash
so in order to access this hash
we simply need to pass in the key of the
value that we want to access
both of the keys in this hash are
strings
so let's pass in the string joesmith
as our key and i'm going to output the
return value
and we'll see that empty hash
and we do
now that we know that this returns the
value of this key which
is a hash we can perform element
assignment on this hash
and to do that we simply need to pass in
the key
so let's call our key email and we'll
use a symbol here
and assign this
to the element in our contact data
array and we already saw how to access
that above with that code on line 6.
so i'm going to output our contacts hash
and this time we expect to see the hash
that is the value of the key joe smith
populated with one key value pair
and that'll be the email information
and that's what we see in our line of
output
so now let's work on moving the rest of
the information
associated with joe smith into the hash
i'm going to copy our line of code on
line 8
and now we'll edit the code on lines 9
and 10 appropriately
so we've moved the email into our hash
and the next step
is the address
so we'll name the key in this hash
address
and lastly
phone
now since all of the information about
joe smith
is in the first sub-array of our contact
data array
we always want to initially reference
the element at index 0 of contact data
the second element reference that we
chain on is what we're going to want to
change
so the address information is at index 1
of the subarray
and the phone information is at index 2.
now we expect to see all three key value
pairs
in the joe smith hash inside of our
contacts hash
for now the hash associated with the key
sally johnson
should still be empty
so we'll run our code and output this
and that looks like just what we
expected
now let's move the information about
sally johnson
into the hash associated with that key
again i'll paste this line of code but
we need to update it appropriately
so the value that we need to return is
associated with the key
sally johnson
and we'll update the keys of our hash
to call them email address and phone
just like we did with joe smith
now when we're performing element
reference on the contact data array we
need to update
which subarray we're accessing the first
sub-array contains all of the
information
relevant to joe smith because we now
want to access the elements that are
relevant to sally
we need to pass in the index 1 instead
of 0.
within that second sub array the
information about sally
is in the same order as the information
about joe
at index 0 is the email information
at index 1 is the address
and at index 2 is the phone number
now on line 14 when we output the
contacts
hash we'll expect to see our two key
value pairs
and both values will be hashes with
three of their own key value pairs
so at this point we expect that all of
the information will be populated in
these hashes
and that's what we see